If you're asking that question, you're measuring
the WRONG things.
Because Connor McDavid isn't worth $8 million to your organization.
He's worth 30 to $40 million per year.
The problem isn't the numbers.
The problem is understanding how sport revenue
works DIFFERENTLY than almost any other business.
There's a revenue ecosystem at play
here—interdependencies that your CFO's
spreadsheet will never capture.
Media deals that hinge on star power.
Sponsorships that activate around marquee players.
Betting handles that spike
when the best player in the world takes the ice.
This week, you're going to learn how to see that ecosystem.
You'll map
five major revenue streams in professional sport.
You'll understand why they're
interdependent.
And by the end, you'll be able to defend that $100 million
contract to a skeptical board—with numbers they can't argue with.
But first, I want to know:
Do you ALREADY have the knowledge to solve this problem?
Can you explain where that missing $22-32
million comes from?
Right now, before you learn
anything this week, test yourself.
Take the
diagnostic exercise that follows this video.
Be honest.
Reveal your knowledge
gaps NOW—so we can fill them together.
Let's find out what you already know...
and what you're about to discover.