Serena Williams' career generated nearly $95
million in prize money over 27 years.
Her endorsement earnings over her career were substantial.
Yet her total brand equity—including her ventures, media presence,
and business ownership—represents significantly more value than
either of those components alone.
So where does that additional brand value come from?
How do you BUILD a brand worth 5 times your on-field earnings?
Here's what I've learned: Elite brand value isn't built on
performance alone.
Serena is one of the greatest athletes ever, but so are dozens of
tennis players who never reached 10 percent of her brand equity.
The difference is strategic brand architecture.
Which revenue streams to prioritize.
When to invest in post-career assets.
How to build equity in businesses you OWN, not just endorse.
This week, you'll learn how elite athletes build
substantial personal brands.
You'll understand the five revenue streams athletes use—and which
create long-term wealth versus short-term income.
You'll explore why women's sports are attracting
significant investment.
And you'll analyze strategic decisions that build generational wealth.
But first: Can you already explain where that brand value comes from?
Take the diagnostic exercise next.
Reveal your gaps now—so we can fill them together.