Executives at heritage sports properties face an
impossible choice: Preserve tradition and watch revenues decline, or
innovate aggressively and risk losing your soul.
Imagine you're CEO of a heritage institution.
Your institution generates steady annual revenue—respectable, but
flat over several years.
Your board proposes transformation: VR experiences, AI-powered tours,
pop-ups in new markets.
The projections show you could increase annual revenue substantially.
But there's a catch.
Your curatorial staff resigns in protest—they call it
commercialization.
Long-time members cancel.
Donors who value authenticity threaten to leave.
If you lose credibility, you lose donations AND your position as the
authoritative voice in your field.
The question isn't "Can we make more money?" It's "Can we grow
WITHOUT losing what makes us valuable?"
This is the heritage monetization dilemma.
You can't just apply Weeks 1-4 frameworks.
Revenue matters, but so does authenticity.
Media strategy works, but not if it commodifies your history.
This week, you'll learn frameworks for balancing
tradition with innovation.
You'll hear from executives who've made these decisions.
And you'll develop your own strategic vision.
But first: Could you solve this now?
If I gave you this challenge, could you increase revenue while
preserving credibility?
Take the diagnostic to find out.