Sports bettors watch 40% more
live sports than non-bettors.
They engage 3x more on digital platforms.
They spend 2x more on merchandise.
That's why betting operators pay premium sponsorship rates.
Betting transforms passive
viewers into active participants.
When you have money on a game, every play matters.
That engagement translates to longer viewing times, more ad exposure,
and higher brand recall.
For sponsors, bettors are the ultimate target audience—engaged,
affluent, and trackable.
Traditional sponsors struggle to prove ROI.
How do you connect a jersey logo to shoe sales?
Betting operators don't have this problem.
Every customer has an account.
Every bet is tracked.
When FanDuel or DraftKings sponsors the NBA, they know exactly how
many customers came from broadcast exposure vs.
social media vs. stadium signage.
That attribution data is worth billions.
This is why betting sponsors pay 20-30% premiums
over traditional sponsors.
They're not just buying impressions—they're buying customers with
measurable lifetime value.
A sports betting customer is worth $500-1,500 in lifetime revenue.
If sponsorship drives 100,000 new customers, that's
$50-150 million in value.
Next, you'll use the Betting Economics Calculator to model customer
acquisition costs, lifetime value, and the ROI of
betting-integrated sponsorships.