How do leaders decide where to
invest in sports partnerships?
How do they measure success?
A common mistake: thinking the rights fee is the investment.
Wrong.
For every $1 in rights fees, brands spend $2-3 on activation.
If we pay $5 million to sponsor a team, we'll spend $10-15 million
amplifying it through ads, hospitality, content, and retail.
The real question isn't "Can we afford the rights?"—it's "Can we
activate at scale?"
We measure three layers: Reach—how many people saw our brand?
Engagement—did they interact?
And Conversion—did they buy?
Reach is easy—broadcast impressions, social media views.
Engagement requires data partnerships—app downloads, website visits.
Conversion is hardest—tying sales to sponsorship exposure.
That's where betting partnerships excel.
When we partner with FanDuel or DraftKings, we access first-party
data: who bet, what they bet on, when they converted.
That attribution loop is impossible with traditional jersey sponsors.
Sports betting operators offer co-marketing deals where we share
customer acquisition costs and conversion data.
It's why betting-integrated sponsorships command 20-30% premiums.
Your activation plan this week needs to answer: What's the reach?
What's the engagement mechanism?
How do we measure conversion?
Think like a CFO, not just a marketer.