FanDuel and DraftKings entered the market
aggressively following the 2018 Supreme Court decision that legalized
sports betting across states.
They pursued rapid expansion through substantial marketing
investments and sponsorship partnerships.
When sports betting legalized state-by-state
starting in May 2018, operators faced a strategic choice: acquire
customers now to establish market presence, or move cautiously and
risk losing market share.
FanDuel and DraftKings chose aggressive expansion—spending heavily on
customer acquisition to build first-mover advantage in new markets.
FanDuel's sponsorship strategy focuses on market penetration and
customer acquisition.
Every NFL partnership, every stadium sponsorship, and every broadcast
integration has a clear goal: drive customer adoption through
increased visibility.
Unlike traditional sponsors measuring "brand awareness," betting
operators measure cost-per-install and conversion metrics directly
tied to business outcomes.
Here's the case dilemma: What's the path to profitability?
Aggressive market entry requires substantial investment.
The question becomes: How do operators transition from customer
acquisition to sustainable profitability?
Your analysis should evaluate unit economics and the factors that
determine long-term viability in this market.
As you read the FanDuel case, focus on customer economics:
acquisition costs, lifetime value, retention rates,
and the timeline to profitability.
The AI Case Coach will help you analyze these metrics.