For 50 years, sports media economics were simple:
Broadcast games on TV, sell ads, make money.
Then streaming arrived.
Linear TV vs. Streaming: Fundamentally different economics.
Let's compare them side-by-side.
Revenue Models.
Linear TV: Advertising at 70-80% plus carriage fees at 20-30%.
Cable providers distribute sports networks to subscribers.
Ad rates: $40-70 per thousand viewers for premium sports.
Streaming: Subscriptions at 80-95% plus optional ads at 5-20%.
Fans pay $10-30 per month directly.
More predictable revenue—subscribers pay monthly
regardless of viewership.
Key difference: Linear monetizes audience.
Streaming monetizes subscribers.
Cost Structures.
Linear TV: Rights fees at 60-70% plus production at 20-30% plus low
distribution costs.
Infrastructure already exists—cable networks.
Streaming: Rights fees at 40-50% plus technology at 25-35% plus
customer acquisition at 20-30%.
Must build platform from scratch—$50-100M initial investment.
Customer acquisition cost: $50-200 per subscriber.
Front-loaded costs—heavy Year 1-3 investment.
Profitability Timelines.
Linear TV: Immediate if priced right.
If ad revenue plus carriage fees exceeds rights plus production,
you're profitable Day 1.
But assumes stable viewership—cord-cutting risk.Streaming: 3-5 years
using customer lifetime value model.
Year 1-2: Heavy losses building platform, acquiring customers.
Year 3-4: Approaching break-even.
Year 5+: Profitability.
Requires customer lifetime value exceeding customer
acquisition cost.Key Risks.
Linear TV: Cord-cutting, audience fragmentation,
generational shift.
Canadian market: Traditional pay TV declined from approximately 11.2
million subscribers in 2014 to 9.7 million in 2024—about 13% decline
over a decade.Streaming: High churn, price sensitivity, competition
from tech giants, technology costs.
Sports-specific streaming services experience higher seasonal churn
driven by sports calendar variations.
Most successful strategy?
Hybrid.
Maintain linear TV cash flow while building streaming for the
future.The risk?
Cord-cutting cannibalizes faster than streaming grows.
This is what happened to Rogers—lost cable subscribers before gaining
enough streaming subscribers.In your simulation, you'll choose:
Linear, streaming, or hybrid?