I want to start Week 3 with a
problem that haunts every CMO I know.
Major brands spend hundreds of millions of dollars annually on sports
sponsorships globally.
For example, Nike's comprehensive sports sponsorship portfolio spans
every league, athlete, and major property you can think of.
Your CFO looks at this budget and asks: What are we
getting for this investment?
So you show them the metrics: billions of social media impressions,
billions of TV viewers reached, high brand
awareness among sports fans.
And they ask the killer follow-up: How many shoes did that sell?
Silence.
Because here's the uncomfortable truth: most sponsorship ROI is fuzzy.
We measure impressions, not conversions.
But something changed in 2018.
Sports betting legalization created sponsors who CAN measure
conversion: FanDuel, DraftKings, BetMGM.
When a betting operator sponsors a team, they know exactly how many
people downloaded the app, placed a bet, and became customers.
That attribution loop changes everything about sponsorship valuation.
This week, you'll learn to think like both
sides: the brand trying to prove ROI, and the
betting operator who actually can.
By the end of this week, you'll design an activation plan that
answers the CFO's question with data, not hope.