Why does Coca-Cola pay FIFA hundreds of millions
to sponsor the World Cup?
Because 3.5 billion people watch it— but that's
not the whole story.
Sponsorship has two costs: rights fees—what you pay the property—and
activation costs—what you spend amplifying the partnership.
If a brand pays a property $300M per year in rights, they'll spend
$600-900M in activation— ads during matches,
retail displays, hospitality, branded content.
The rights fee is just the entry ticket.
In exchange, sponsors receive three things.
First, Reach—logo exposure across broadcasts, stadiums, anddigital.
Second, Engagement—branded activations,
hospitality, fan experiences.
Third, Category exclusivity—major sponsors block
competitors from the same tournament.
That exclusivity premium is worth 30-50% of the rights fee alone.
Brands measure sponsorship like advertising: cost per thousand
impressions, or CPM.
Premium sports advertising reaches $5,000-10,000 CPM.
Sponsorship properties typically command lower CPMs based on
frequency and context.
Why lower CPM?
Frequency.
Fans see a jersey sponsor 20-30 times per season.
That repetition builds brand recall better than one-time ads.
Next, you'll use the Sponsorship Valuation
Calculator to model real deals.
Input reach, frequency, and costs to calculate CPM and exposure
value— the first step in ROI analysis.