While media rights and ticketing depend on the
game itself, two revenue streams are driven by brand value:
sponsorship and merchandising.
Let's see how teams monetize their brands through corporate
partnerships and consumer products.
Sponsorship: 15 to 25% of Revenue.
The most visible sponsorship deals are naming rights: Scotiabank
Arena in Toronto—$800 million over 20 years.
That's $40 million per year just for the name.
Jersey sponsorship arrived in North America in 2017.
The NBA allows a 2.5-inch patch on uniforms.
Top deals reach $20-30 million per year—Golden State Warriors and
Rakuten, $20 million annually.
But the best sponsors don't just buy logos—they create experiences.
Scotiabank's "Scene plus Night" at Leafs games integrates their
loyalty program with ticket offers and in-arena experiences.
Fans remember positive moments, not just a logo.
Key sponsorship categories: - Naming rights (15-50 Million/year) -
Jersey/uniform patches (5-30Million/year) - Category
partnerships—official bank, beer, airline (500
thousand-10Million/year).
Merchandising: 5-10% of Revenue.
Most major North American leagues— NFL, NHL,
MLB— use a centralized model.
The league manages all licensing, then splits
revenue equally among teams.
Why?
Competitive balance.
This prevents the Yankees and Cowboys from dominating merchandise
sales and creating massive revenue gaps.
Revenue spikes during championship runs—sales see significant
increases during peak playoff performance.
Star acquisitions drive dramatic spikes— when
LeBron James signed with the Lakers, his jersey sales saw a 600%
spike within hours of the announcement.
New designs generate consistent revenue—NBA
"City Edition" jerseys generate over $100 million annually.
Digital commerce transformed merchandising—teams now sell globally
without retail partnerships.
Key insight: These are
brand-driven revenue streams.
The stronger your brand, the more valuable your sponsorship inventory
and the more merchandise you sell.
Next up: Betting—the newest and fastest-growing revenue frontier.