Congratulations!
You've completed five weeks of the Business of Sports Marketing.
You now have frameworks that working professionals use to make
million-dollar decisions.
Let's connect everything before your capstone.
Week 1 taught you revenue ecosystems—the five
streams and how they interconnect.
Week 2 showed you media rights economics—how streaming changes
valuations and the risks of long-term contracts.
Week 3 covered sponsorship and betting—ROI frameworks and the
attribution advantage.
Week 4 explored athlete brands and emerging sports—the five revenue
streams and evaluation frameworks.
Week 5 added the final piece: Heritage and future trends.
Not everything should be optimized for short-term revenue.
Sometimes preservation creates long-term value.
Your capstone project—developing a strategy for an emerging sports
franchise—requires you to integrate all five weeks.
You're not just designing a brand.
You're building a business case that considers:
Revenue ecosystem design from Week 1.
Media rights implications from Week 2.
Sponsorship strategy from Week 3.
Market positioning and athlete partnerships from Week 4.
And heritage balance and future trends from Week 5.
Your strategy needs to achieve multiple objectives.
It should build sustainable revenue across all five streams.
It should position your franchise competitively.
It should be financially viable from day one.
This is real strategic thinking.
The frameworks you've learned aren't academic exercises—they're the
same tools executives use to make these decisions.
Good luck with your capstone.
You have everything you need.
Now show us what you can build.