This case study isn't about hockey specifically.
It's about every heritage property facing the same dilemma: How do
you grow without becoming something you're not?
The case presents a real strategic tension.
The Hockey Hall of Fame generates revenue from
admission, retail, and hospitality.
The board wants to propose growth initiatives that could
substantially increase annual revenue.
The staff and donors want to preserve the institution's integrity.
Both sides have legitimate arguments.
Here's what makes this case hard: The growth opportunities ARE real.
VR experiences could attract younger audiences.
International pop-ups could tap new markets.
The revenue projections aren't fantasy.
But the risks are also real.
Heritage institutions that over-commercialize lose
credibility permanently.
Once you're perceived as a theme park, you can't go back to being a
serious cultural institution.
The curatorial staff and donors aren't being stubborn—they're
protecting something valuable.
Your analysis should avoid two traps.
Trap one: Assuming growth always wins.
Sometimes preservation IS the strategy.
Trap two: Assuming tradition always wins.
Institutions that refuse all change become irrelevant.
Where exactly is the line between acceptable innovation and
mission-compromise?
That line is different for every organization—your job is to find
where it is for a heritage institution.
As you watch the executive interviews, note how each leader defines
their boundaries.
Their answers reveal different philosophies about heritage and growth.