Unlike most industries, professional sports
leagues NEED their competitors to thrive.
Why?
Because competitive balance creates a better product—and makes
everyone more money.
This is the logic behind revenue sharing.
Model 1: NFL—Maximum sharing, 60% shared.
Nearly all revenue is shared equally.
Result?
The Green Bay Packers— a city with a population of 105,000—generate
similar revenue to the New York Giants.
Highest competitive parity in sports.
Model 2: NHL—Moderate Sharing, 50% shared.
National media rights, streaming, and merchandise are shared.
Local media rights and ticket sales stay with teams.
Plus a revenue sharing pool for struggling teams.
The complication?
Canadian teams earn in Canadian dollars but pay
players in U.S. dollars.
Currency fluctuations create major challenges.
Model 3: Premier League—Tiered Distribution.
TV revenue split three ways: 50% equal, 25% based on finishing
position, 25% based on TV appearances.
Rewards success while maintaining baseline competitiveness.
Why this matters: Revenue sharing limits strategic
options, creates governance tensions, and affects team valuations.
In the Vancouver Canucks case, you'll see how revenue sharing—and
currency headwinds—affect strategic decisions.