Women's sports sponsorship is
experiencing rapid growth.
The NWSL quadrupled sponsorship revenue over five years to reach
approximately $60 million in 2024.
The WNBA more than doubled its sponsorship revenue
to $55 million in the same period.
This isn't charity—it's smart money recognizing an undervalued asset.
Here's the investment thesis.
Women's sports audiences are growing rapidly.
The 2023 Women's World Cup drew significant global viewership.
Women's college basketball viewership has surged.
Yet sponsorship dollars lag far behind—women's sports still represent
a small percentage of total sports sponsorship spending.
That gap is the opportunity.
Why now?
Three converging factors.
First, media coverage finally caught up—streaming platforms need
content, and women's sports deliver engaged audiences.
Second, brands discovered that women's sports fans are more loyal and
more likely to purchase from sponsors.
Third, athletes like Serena Williams, Megan Rapinoe, and Caitlin
Clark proved individual stars can drive massive engagement.
The smart money is moving fast.
Major media companies are securing women's sports rights.
Financial services brands are becoming jersey
sponsors and official partners.
Investment rounds are filling up quickly.
These aren't feel-good investments—they're bets on a market that's
been underpriced for decades.
The question for brands: Do you sponsor women's sports now while
valuations are relatively low, or wait until prices catch up?
Your analysis should factor in this growth trajectory.