Heritage properties face a unique constraint: Your
authenticity IS your asset.
Monetize too aggressively, and you destroy the very
thing people value.
But refuse to evolve, and you become irrelevant.
Use the Heritage Balance Grid.
On one axis: Revenue Impact—how much money does this generate?
On the other axis: Authenticity Risk—how much does
this threaten our credibility?
Plot every opportunity on this grid.
High revenue, low risk: Digital archive access,
expanded merchandise, membership tiers.
These are obvious wins.
Low revenue, high risk: Branded experiences that feel disconnected
from mission, entertainment-first initiatives.
These require extreme caution.
The dangerous quadrant is high revenue, high risk.
An initiative might generate significant revenue, but if stakeholders
perceive it as inconsistent with your mission,
donors and members revolt.
The question isn't whether it makes money—it's whether it makes money
AND preserves what matters.
Here's the key insight: Authenticity is not binary.
You can extend reach without replacing substance.
Digital access to archives serves your mission AND generates revenue.
That's alignment.
Three tests for any initiative.
First, does it serve your mission or replace it?
Mission-aligned programs vs. mission-compromising programs.
Second, would your most loyal stakeholders accept it?
If core community members say "that's not who we
are," listen carefully.
Third, is it reversible?
Experiments are fine; permanent damage isn't.
The executives you'll hear from use versions of this framework—but
they draw the lines in different places.
Watch for where they agree and where they diverge.