November 2013: Rogers Communications paid $5.2
billion for exclusive Canadian NHL rights—12 years,
all platforms, all games.
The largest sports media deal in Canadian history.
This deal presented a case study in media market disruption and
strategic challenges.
Rogers' Three Strategic Goals:
Goal 1: Defend cable subscribers.
They believed NHL rights would prevent cord-cutting.
Reality: Canadian traditional TV subscriptions declined significantly
during the contract period.
Hockey alone couldn't reverse the industry shift to streaming.
Goal 2: Build streaming dominance.
They projected 1+ million Sportsnet NOW subscribers.
Reality: They reached only 450,000 by 2024—
missing targets substantially every year.
Goal 3: Brand positioning.
Become Canada's #1 sports network.
Partial success: Sportsnet built brand equity,
though questions remained about profitability margins.
Rogers' annual rights fees escalated from $300
million to $500 million across the contract period.
The streaming platform did not generate sufficient offsetting revenue
from subscriptions and advertising.
COVID Impact: 2020-21 season cancellation created payment pressures.
Rogers paid full rights fees while generating minimal live content
and had limited ability to renegotiate terms.
Lessons learned: Content alone isn't enough—streaming experience and
platform architecture matter.
Long-term rights deals require flexibility clauses
for market disruptions.
Media landscape disruption creates risks for
fixed-price, multi-year commitments.
In Week 2, you'll analyze this deal in depth and examine what Rogers'
strategic options are as the market evolves.