Amazon paid $1 billion per year
for NFL Thursday Night Football.
Rogers paid $5.2 billion over 12 years for NHL Canadian rights.
How do media companies decide what sports content is worth?
The Five-Factor Valuation Framework.
Factor 1: Audience Size and Demographics.
Larger, more valuable audiences command higher prices.
NFL regular season games average 17-19 million viewers with premium
demographics—males 18-49, a demographic with a high income.
Advertisers pay $50 to $70 per thousand
viewers—double non-sports rates.
Here's a critical point: Model viewership
trends, not just current numbers.
Rogers assumed stable NHL ratings.
They experienced ratings declines of 12% or more in recent seasons.
That's hundreds of millions in lost revenue.
Factor 2: Exclusivity and Competition.
More bidders equals higher prices.
Exclusive rights cost 2-3x more than non-exclusive.
When Amazon, Apple, and traditional networks
compete for NFL rights, prices skyrocket.
NFL deal increased significantly from 2011 to 2022, driven by
competitive bidding among multiple platforms.
Factor 3: Content Volume and Scheduling.
Quality matters more than quantity.
One NFL primetime game is worth 10-15 mid-week NHL games.
Concentrated scheduling windows—NFL Sundays—create predictable
audience habits and higher per-game value.
Factor 4: Brand Alignment and Sponsorship.
Sponsorship revenue can subsidize 20-35% of rights costs.
Strong brand alignment with sponsor categories (automotive, beer,
financial services) creates premium sponsorship opportunities.
Without sponsorship integration, profitability
becomes harder to achieve.
Factor 5: Platform Strategy Fit.
Sometimes you pay more than a property is "worth"
because it serves strategic goals.
Amazon's $1 billion per year for NFL drives subscriber acquisition
and loyalty for Prime membership, with reported record Prime sign-ups
during NFL broadcasts.
However, strategic value must be measurable and achievable.
Warning: Strategic value
justifications must be grounded in data.
Rogers justified overpaying with "subscriber defense" logic—but
couldn't prove the relationship between NHL rights
and subscriber retention.
When subscribers left anyway, the case collapsed.NFL deal increased
significantly from 2011 to 2022, driven by competitive bidding among
multiple platforms.
The Five Factors: Audience Size and Demographics.
Exclusivity and Competition.
Content Volume and Scheduling.
Brand Alignment and Sponsorship.
Platform Strategy Fit.In the Streaming Wars simulation, you'll apply
this framework to make your own billion-dollar decisions.