Pickleball has grown dramatically in recent years.
Padel is the fastest-growing racket sport in Europe.
Esports viewership rivals traditional sports.
How do you evaluate whether to invest in an emerging sport?
Use the four-factor framework.
Factor one: Demographic breadth.
Does it appeal to multiple age groups?
Broader appeal means staying power.
Narrow demographics create growth risk if the audience doesn't expand.
Factor two: Accessibility.
Can anyone play?
Low barriers to entry mean faster adoption.
Factor three: Media viability.
Can it be broadcast or streamed?
Some sports work on traditional media, others
thrive on digital platforms.
Understand the broadcast economics before investing.
Factor four: Monetization infrastructure.
Are there leagues, tours, venues?
You need commercial structure to create sponsorship opportunities.
Without structure, there's no revenue model.
Apply this to emerging sports opportunities.
Each property has different strengths and weaknesses.
Some have demographic breadth but limited infrastructure.
Others have strong media properties but narrow audiences.
The right answer depends on your timeline and risk tolerance.
Your analyst's interview shows how to validate emerging sports
opportunities before scaling.
Watch for the proof-of-concept methodology—that's how professional
investors evaluate new markets.